{
    "id": "c32e18cfd0cc496898543819c464f2c9",
    "title": "Sentence Agreement Excerise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "86e40fd0b4de4ea3a8b3a507b24d7075",
            "title": "Sentence Agreement Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Every room …………….. been cleaned.",
                    "description": "We use every before a singular noun. The verb is also singular.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has",
                        "have",
                        "was"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Each new day …………………. different.",
                    "description": "We use each before a singular noun. The verb is also singular.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "are",
                        "has"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Natives of India …………….. black hair.",
                    "description": "Here the plural verb ‘have’ agrees with the plural subject ‘natives’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has",
                        "have",
                        "having"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The climate of London …………….. not suit my health.",
                    "description": "Here the subject is the singular noun ‘climate’ and hence we use the singular verb ‘does’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "does",
                        "do",
                        "has"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "My sister and I ……………… pleased to accept your invitation.",
                    "description": "When two singular nouns are connected by ‘and’ the verb should be plural.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "am",
                        "are"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Each one of these apples …………….. red.",
                    "description": "We use a singular verb after each one and every one.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "has",
                        "are",
                        "have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The whole class ……………… listening to the speech.",
                    "description": "The expression ‘the whole class’ indicates a single entity and therefore we use a singular verb with it.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "were",
                        "have",
                        "has"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "My sister and my brother ……………… at the party.",
                    "description": "When two singular nouns are connected by and, they take a plural verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "were",
                        "have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She and I …………….. having dinner together.",
                    "description": "When two singular nouns are connected by and, they take a plural verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "were",
                        "have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Neither red nor green ……………… me.",
                    "description": "The verb is singular when 'neither' and 'nor' connect two singular nouns.",
                    "answers": [
                        "suit",
                        "suits",
                        "suiting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Either Jack or Peter ……………. to clean the room.",
                    "description": "When we connect two nouns with ‘either…or’, the verb agrees with the noun after ‘or’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has",
                        "have",
                        "are"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The President, as well as the Prime Minister, ……………… visiting Moscow.",
                    "description": "We can connect two subjects with as well as. If the first subject is singular, the verb is also singular.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "are",
                        "have",
                        "has"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}